["Money for Nothing"
by Dire Straits]
♪ MTV... ♪
[music]
[sniffs]
- Could've done without the
anatomy lesson, but that's okay.
I'll work that shit
out in therapy.
- Well, Beth...
That's a risk you take when
you sneak into a man's bedroom
in the middle of the night.
- Don't I know it.
- And a drink.
Oof!
This news must be
real good or real bad.
- In my 37 years,
I've only spent the night
here alone once.
You know, houses,
they don't make noises
when they're full of people
but when they're empty...
Man, they moan and they creak
and they shift in place.
I thought the house was going
to tear itself out
from the foundation
and walk away.
So, I figured that I would
just spend the night
and make sure it doesn't walk
away with you.
- I don't uh...
I don't mind an empty house.
- Mm.
Liar.
- I'll, uh...
I'll get your room ready.
- Oh, my room's
ready enough, Dad.
- You ready to turn in?
- You kidding?
I'm five away from sleep.
Look, I can go downstairs.
- No, no, honey.
No, you're...
You're fine right there.
[groans]
What are you reading?
- "The Solace of Open Spaces."
"To be tough is to be fragile.
To be tender is
to be truly fierce."
- "True solace is finding none.
Which is to say,
it's everywhere."
- Yeah.
Not sure I believe that.
- It's true, Beth.
Can't be found.
Lord knows I've looked.
No... Solace...
must be discovered.
- Discovered how?
I need an example, 'cause, um...
Well, I've looked
everywhere, too.
- [sighs]
I spent all evening on
the porch staring at mountains,
listening to birds...
Heart still empty.
I take a shower
to wash it away like dirt
but you can't wash lonely off.
So, I surrender to it.
Best I can do
is sleep through the lonely,
if I can sleep at all.
Then I walk in here
and I discover you.
Now my heart's full.
I sure hope you
outlive me, Beth.
I'm not sure I could tolerate
the world without you in it.
- Worry not, Daddy.
Only the good die young.
If a meteor strikes
earth tonight,
it is me and the cockroaches
running this
motherfucker tomorrow.
- [chuckles]
Well, I guess tomorrow's
my lucky day, then.
Good night, baby girl.
- Good night, Daddy.
[music]
[chanting]
- Thank you.
- He needed this.
- We both do.
- Find us a house to rent.
We're done living with
fathers for a little while.
- [sighs]
I feel better already.
In my soul.
- That's all that matters.
[chanting continues]
[music]
- Is he okay?
- Well...
He's a boy who was forced
to do what men do.
These days, most men
won't even do it.
because society has taught
them that they are sheep.
And when wolves come
you must not fight them.
You must call a shepherd.
So, he feels guilt
for doing something
he should be praised for.
A few more sweats, then Mo
will take him up on the hill.
Then when he comes down,
he won't think of
himself as a killer.
He'll think of
himself as a warrior.
Like you.
- I'm hardly a warrior.
- How much guilt do you feel?
- My only regret is that
I didn't kill him myself.
- [chuckles]
- That's a warrior's regret.
[music]
- Give that horse
to Mia today, Lloyd.
Pull that new bay
from the mare corral.
She needs ridin'.
[sinister music]
- This is my mount.
I ain't riding a fucking mare.
- Then you'll walk.
And take that boy and show him
how to saddle a horse.
- C'mon, kid.
Memorise what I say:
Horn, pommel,
skirt, seat, rigging...
Repeat it.
- Horn, pommel,
skirt, seat, rigging.
- Cinch, latigo,
stirrup...
D rings.
Back billet.
- Cinch, latigo, stirrup,
D rings, back billet.
- Good.
Let's toss it on her.
[horse whinnies]
Okay, go.
Okay, reach under her
and grab that cinch.
- Cinch.
- Okay, latigo goes
through your D-ring.
Back up and through.
Back through that D-ring again.
Pull it up snug.
Good, now the same thing
on the back cinch.
- [exhales]
- All right.
Now this is your latigo keeper.
It's got the name of
the saddlemaker right on it.
Can you read?
- Yeah.
- Okay. I ride a Sterling.
Mister Dutton, he rides
a Dale Harwood or a Don Rich.
And Rip, he rides
an Andy Maschke.
- What do the others ride?
- Don't matter.
They saddle their own horses.
- Lloyd, when you're
done with that,
start moving them panels
into the arena.
[sinister music]
[beep]
- Yes, sir?
- Can you get the
state prison warden
on the line for me, please?
- Of course.
[beep]
Sir, Warden Jeffries
is on line one.
- How are you, sir?
Does he have
a public defender or counsel?
Thank you.
[exhales]
Attorney General Dutton
for Richard Scott.
Mr. Scott, I need to interview
your client Terrell Riggins
in regards to his involvement
in the John Dutton
attempted murder.
That won't be necessary.
Because I'm offering
him immunity.
- Shit!
What the fuck is that?
- That's a centipede.
It get you?
- Uh, yeah.
It got me.
- Most people in Texas
don't sleep on the ground.
I brought you some breakfast.
- [grunts]
You got a fork?
- Make a sandwich out of it.
Who are you?
- I'm Jimmy.
I'm the new cowboy.
- [chuckles]
You're not a cowboy.
- What makes you say that?
- I can see it in your eyes.
You're somebody somebody
told to come here
so we can make
a cowboy out of you.
- Something like that.
- It's the most glorious
work you can do
that nobody ever sees.
Takes every inch of you.
You're gonna risk your life
and your horse's life.
And nobody's knows
if you won or if you lost.
It's art...
without an audience
'til the day you die.
And then after you're dead,
you don't have an
audience either.
You just...[pfft]
You're just...you're just gone.
Now, you gotta want this life.
You've got to want it
all the way to your bones.
And if you don't...
it can be absolute
hell on earth.
- I don't know what I want.
- There's a few of us
old goats hanging around.
We'll make sure
you don't starve.
Oh, and quit sleeping
on the ground.
Find yourself
a bench or something.
Otherwise you'll find yourself
cozied up next to a rattlesnake.
- Bench. Got it.
[clears throat]
[music]
- Got me something saddled?
- We're just going to gather
two-year olds.
Hell, we'll be back in
a half an hour.
That's when all the fun starts.
- Well, I ain't breaking no
colts, for crying out loud.
This is the only fun
I get today.
- Boy, let's see
what you've learnt.
Saddle Blaze for Mister Dutton.
- It's already saddled.
- Well, go on and get him.
- Still "boy", huh?
- Yeah, he ain't gonna be around
long enough to name, sir.
- Yeah, well, if he's that bad
at shoveling shit,
I damn sure don't want
him saddling my horse.
- [chuckles]
He can shovel shit
with the best of them,
but he got on the wrong side
of your daughter, though.
- Hmm.
- All right.
- Check your cinch.
- Handsome little sucker,
aren't you?
I bet that's the cause
behind every problem you got.
If I was you I'd find
a way to get ugly.
- Ugly?
- And how.
- Why ugly?
Handsome's the only thing
I got going for me.
- That's why.
[music]
[shouting]
- Can you send some
more deputies
to the field office
in Livingston?
Some sort of protest.
Everybody back up.
You cannot block the entrance
to a government building.
[shouting]
- You're the fucking animal!
[grunts]
Everybody down!
On the ground!
I'm sick of this shit.
Keep them on the ground.
Don't shoot anybody.
- Hey!
- Put the rocks down!
- Don't even think about it.
[sirens blaring]
- Kayce, what the fucking fuck?
- You tell me.
They just showed up pouring
blood on themselves
and throwing rocks and shit.
I don't even know what
the fuck they want.
- This is what they want,
they want the fucking
shit show, Kayce.
And you just gave it to them.
- Fuck. Hendon, put the
goddamn gun in your holster.
This is Haskell.
[music]
[whinnying]
- All right, here we go.
Jake.
You're sorrel bald face
filly with four
stocking feet.
- Ethan, bay colt, Blaze.
- Sir.
- Ryan, Colby, you'll be
Buckskin filly and dun Colt.
And Walker, you're red rhone.
blaze face.
- Something happen?
- I'm working it out.
- Yeah, I see that.
So can the whole ranch.
- Well, they need
to see it, sir.
- I don't want to hear about the
wildfire that got away from you.
Just the one you put out.
- Yessir.
- Whatever he did,
don't forget who he is to you.
To both of us.
- Who he is to us, sir,
is the reason why
he's still walking.
[phone ringing]
- Yeah.
There's what?
Oh, jeez.
All right.
I'm on my way.
Ryan.
Let's go work for the state.
- What happened?
- I don't even know
how to explain it.
[booing, shouting]
- Son, if I spent
a week thinking of ways
to fuck up my day, I could not
have come up with this.
- Where's EMS?
- It ain't blood.
It's paint, I think.
They, uh, poured it
on themselves.
- Poured it on themselves?
- Yep.
- You ever seen anything
like this before?
- Not since my bachelor party.
- Why would you do that?
- Ryan, Ryan,
don't talk to them.
- Was this all by the book?
- 100%, Kayce was assaulted
and rushed by the crowd,
he used justified force
to subdue his assailant.
Hendon came to his aide,
they controlled the crowd
until we got here.
- You got video to back that up?
- Oh, there's
no shortage of video, John.
I'm sure the whole world's
watching this shit as we speak.
- Who's the ring leader
of this circus?
- One on the left, blonde hair.
She's been arrested
in Berkeley, Houston,
Portland, St. Louis...
Disturbing the peace,
failure to disperse.
All dismissed.
- What's her name?
- Summer Higgins.
[shouting]
- You Summer?
- You must be the big boss.
- I'm the retired big boss.
You can see how
that's working out for me.
I can get them blankets
to cover up if they'd like.
- Our bodies are our protest.
They don't want to cover up,
though I can see it bothers you.
Men objectify our breasts,
and then brainwash the world
into thinking
that they should be hidden
to make up for your jealousy
or lack of impulse control,
which is ironic because nature
didn't make them for you.
Nature made them
to feed children,
not your toxic male fantasies.
- I see.
- But that's not why we're here.
- You don't say.
- We're protesting the existence
of a state-sponsored
police force
that protects industrialised
animal farming
and the mass murder of millions
of animals every year.
- You ever plow a field, Summer?
To plant the quinoa or sorghum
or whatever the hell
it is you eat?
You kill everything on
the ground and under it:
you kill every snake,
every frog,
every mouse, mole,
vole, worm, quail...
You kill them all.
So, I guess the only
real question is:
how cute does an animal
have to be
before you care if
it dies to feed you?
- What the hell are these people
doing all the way out here?
- Of all the places, doesn't
seem too random, does it.
- What do you want to do, Kayce?
- Press charges.
- That's what they want, John.
I mean, they want to see
this on the goddamn news.
- It's already on the news.
Let them stare five years
in the face
and see how many more
protests they want to plan.
- Okay, all right.
Officer.
Let's get her up.
You're under arrest
for aggravated battery
of a peace officer.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Let's go.
Anything you say can and
will be used against you
in a court of law.
If you don't have a lawyer,
one will be appointed to you.
["Cowpoke" by Colter Wall
playing]
♪ I'm lonesome but happy ♪
♪ Rich, but I'm broke ♪
♪ And the good Lord
knows the reason ♪
♪ I'm just a cowpoke ♪
♪ From Cheyenne to Douglas ♪
♪ The ranges I know ♪
♪ Cause I drift with the wind ♪
♪ No-one cares where I go ♪
Woman: Lloyd's chomping
at the bit over there.
♪ I ain't got a dime ♪
♪ In these old worn-out jeans ♪
♪ So I'll stop eating steak ♪
♪ I'll go back to beans ♪
♪ I'll pick up a tenspot ♪
- She's sensible.
Better breeding
program, lately.
Hell, I think this
one's done, boss.
Let's get another.
- Nicely done.
[kissing]
Man: Get him, Ethan!
Yee-hee!
Man: Yes, sir!
Mia: All right, Ethan.
Man: Glad you didn't
get bucked off.
We'd have had Teeter
get on there.
Pretty nice horse
there, boss.
That's a pretty good
first day for him.
Mia: It's beer time.
Teeter: Beer o'clock.
Lick it up, little baby.
- The last three are yours.
- After all I've done for you?
- Lloyd, you start acting
like a boss,
and I'll fucking
treat you like one.
- So I'm low man now
for doing something
you would've done.
- It's only because of what
you've done for me
that you ain't
over there shoveling shit
with that fucking boy.
You're lucky you have any
horses to break at all.
- That son of a bitch
should be dead.
- Goddamn it, Lloyd,
but he ain't.
Mister Dutton wants him here,
so guess what?
He's fucking here.
There ain't nobody that wants
that son of a bitch dead
more than me,
but the ranch comes first.
And you forgot that.
[suspenseful music]
[chattering]
- Come on!
- Come on, Shad.
- Hurry it the fuck up,
you're going to miss it!
- That's your cousin?
- Yep. Come on, baby.
Clean run. Clean run.
Show them how to do it,
smooth run.
Smooth run.
Clean. I want it clean.
Do a clean run for
me this time.
It's all we need,
just got to get this one.
Watch how smooth this is,
watch this. Come on.
- Come on, come on!
- Woo, woo!
- Come on!
- Oh, yeah.
- God damn, that is fast!
- That's how we do it!
- That's roping, motherfucker!
- That's how we do it.
- Mm-hmm.
- Damn, that's good.
- Clearly, the ability
to rope is not hereditary.
- What? Fuck you.
I can out-rope your fucking ass.
- In what fucking world
can you outrope me?
- In any world.
Literally on any fucking planet.
I'll take you to outer-space and
I'll out-rope your fucking ass
in outer-space.
I don't care.
- What the hell kind of roping
are you going to do
in outer space?
It's called gravity.
- What the fuck are you
all talking about,
roping in fucking space?
- He is!
- That's fucking insane.
- Buncha haters.
[chattering]
- You have the same DNA
as that man?
- You're right, I didn't do it
by myself...
[chatter]
What are you talking about--
[knocking]
- Whatcha doin'?
- Nuthin'.
Ain't nothin' to do.
Just waitin' to be tired.
Something wrong?
- Nah.
Get some rest.
Morning comes early.
- Don't know why
everyone calls it morning.
Four a.m. is night time
any way you slice it.
- Yeah, suppose you're right.
Good night.
- What are you doing
out here, babe?
- I'm just kind of tired
of sleeping in that trailer.
Want to sleep out here under the
stars while the weather's good.
If that's all right with you.
- I don't think so.
- No?
- No.
- Why no? You'd rather
sleep in that little box?
- Oh, we can stay out here.
But you're not gettin'
any sleep.
[music]
- [scoffs]
- Eggs over easy, Kayce?
- Yessir, thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Okay, look at this one.
It's in Prior, it's halfway
between here and Bozeman.
It's forty acres.
The house is nice.
I could teach at the rez, get
Tate back with his friends.
- Hey, Dad.
- Hey, buddy.
How you feeling?
- Hungry.
- Four days in a sweat lodge
will do that to you.
- Boy, you ain't lying, Grandpa.
- House looks nice.
- Yeah, I think so too.
- Here you go, Kayce.
- All right.
Grandpa: Okay.
- Not hungry?
- Mm-mm.
I'm intermittent fasting.
- What's that mean?
- Uh, nothing but coffee
and cigarettes 'til noon,
and then I can eat
what the fuck I want
until I start drinking at six.
- I'd like to meet the doctor
who came up with that diet.
- I've adapted it a bit
to suit my lifestyle.
- What are you working on today?
- I got a few irons cooking.
[music]
- What irons?
- I'd rather ask for forgiveness
than permission on these, Daddy.
If you don't mind.
- I do mind.
What irons?
- I'm taking the job
at Market Equities.
- So take the job, then what?
Tell me how that helps us.
- It helps us when I run it
into the fucking ground.
What are you doing today?
- Battling my conscience.
- Mmm.
Well, I'd offer advice, Dad,
but I've never been
in that situation.
[chuckles]
I gotta go.
Love you.
- Mmm.
- Off to ruin a life.
- Okay, honey.
[music]
Fuck it.
[keys jingle]
- You made bail.
- How'd I do that?
[music]
Why'd you bail me out?
- You believe what
you're doing is right.
I disagree but I...
I respect it.
- I can't pay you back.
- Not asking you to.
- You're gonna ask
me something though.
- I'd like to...
I'd like to show you my ranch.
- You think
a tour of your ranch
is gonna change what I believe?
- No, but it might help
you understand me better.
Might help me
understand you, too.
- Surely you can appreciate
that virtually every fiber
of my being is screaming
at me to not get in the pickup
with the charming,
white male in his 50s,
who I don't
know from fucking Adam.
- Charming and in my 50s, huh.
I'm starting to like
you better already.
But I see your point.
It's naive of me.
Don't throw any
more rocks at my son, okay?
- Do I have your word
you're not gonna attack me
and kill me and leave me
in the middle of a forest?
- If my plan was doing all that
I'm probably willing
to break my word.
- I'm going to trust you.
- Good.
I'm gonna trust you, too.
Get in.
[engine starts]
[door buzzes]
[music]
- Full immunity.
- Okay, ask away.
Terrell, you can answer
his questions
without fear of prosecution.
- No matter what I say?
- No matter what you say.
You are a State's Witness.
- What about in here?
Ain't no immunity for a snitch.
- You'll be put
into protective custody.
With good behavior,
we can move you to
a medium security facility
that is significantly
more comfortable
than this place.
- Fire away.
- Do you know this man?
Did this man hire
you to facilitate
the murder attempt
on the Dutton family?
[music]
[knocking]
- Can I help you?
- It's like driving
through a different century.
Are you even aware of the strain
the rest of the world is under?
- I'm aware of the strain here.
- I don't know how much
longer we'll last.
As a people, you know?
I don't think
the planet's going
to tolerate us much longer.
- That's because people
have stopped living with it,
and started living on it.
But you're right.
There will come a time when
Earth sheds us like dead skin.
And it will be our own fault.
- I'm surprised you can
see that from here.
- You can see it
from anywhere, Summer.
It's impossible to miss.
Gayle: Can you accommodate
300 people?
- It's the largest
ranch in Montana.
We can accommodate Denmark.
- The bride is thinking
that during the day
maybe offer trail rides
or hay rides...
- Hay rides at a wedding?
What? They want to fucking
bob for apples
and have sack races too, Gayle?
- They're from New York, Beth.
- Ah.
- They want the ranch
experience.
- Well, I'm just offering
the ranch.
If they want the ranch
experience, price doubles.
- Won't be a problem.
Can you lock
that July 28th date?
- You send me a deposit,
it's all yours.
Gonna lose you.
Gotta go.
[music]
[tires screech]
[ding]
[office phone ringing]
- May I help you?
Excuse me.
Ma'am?
Excuse me!
I called security.
- That's fine.
Close the door, please.
What do you want, Beth?
- That's my seat.
- Your seat?
- Mm-hmm.
That's right, Bobby.
You're sitting in my seat.
[laughs]
Man, I drove seven hours
just to tell you that.
- I have no idea what
you're talking about.
- I am the new president
of Market Equity's
Montana division.
I oversee all new development.
- Oh. That must be quite
the salary they're paying you.
Congratulations.
- Mm-mm.
No salary, Bob.
No stock options.
No percentage of profit.
I wonder if you can guess
what would entice me
to take a job
doing exactly what my family
have been fighting against
for a century.
- Their interest
in Schwartz and Meyer.
- Their controlling
interest, Bob.
Yeah.
You bet on the wrong horse.
You are fired.
You're fired too,
you nosy bitch.
All this shit,
it's moving to Montana.
[music]
- Hard day at the office?
- Yeah, you could say that.
- That's the problem
with secrets.
They don't stay secret forever.
- No. They don't.
- Care to tell me yours?
- You first.
- You did it.
You got away from him.
You got the job you deserve.
You did everything
you said you would do.
Now, I keep my word.
[baby babbles]
Meet your son.
- Come to think Mr. George,
enjoyed them.
He's been quite
a bunk rider,
and, uh, he got to see
a lot of bunk riding
with Salty Chief.
And I never knew
what that was.
They were powerful horses
if you're off by yourself
in the big country.
You didn't want to get
off of one of 'em.
- No, no, you can't
get back on.
[laughing]
They're liable to go back
to the barn without ya.
- Yeah. Mr. George
appreciated the fact
that they had a little
fire in them.
- Yeah, well, I like them to
have a little bit of fire,
but doggone, you don't want
to have a rodeo every day.
- No.
- [laughs]
- He rode that little
paint blue horse
that he'd bought off
of a foreman
that joined the ranch here
that was sure enough
a little cutting horse.
And, uh...
he worked her a lot.
[music]
- You ready?
- Ready for what?
- Ready for work.
Grab your bag, ol' boy.
Let's go.
Hope you soaked up some
of what you heard in there.
- Soaked up some of what?
- There's three gods in Texas:
the Almighty himself,
Buster Welch, and George Strait.
You just met one of them.
- That's not George Strait.
- I hope the Good Lord
gave you a big dick, Jimmie,
'cause he sure
shorted you on brains.
Can you ride?
- Yeah, I can ride.
- Good, 'cause they're
sending us on colts.
- Are they broke?
- Oh, not so much.
But, they will be
when we get there.
- How long a ride is it?
- Oh, through two pastures.
Ten thousand acres each.
Just two, though.
Come on, old boy,
let's saddle up.
[music]
Easy, easy.
- Hey, hey.
- Settle him down.
You ready?
All right, let's run the rank
out of these sons of bitches.
[Flying or Crying
by Zach Bryan playing]
[gate squeaks]
♪ By the end of the night
We'd be flying or crying ♪
♪ Talking 'bout the times ♪
♪ We've spent living
towards dying ♪
♪ So don't stop running, boy
But don't be naive ♪
♪ 'Cause we'll be flying
or crying ♪
♪ By the end of the night ♪
[music]