C'mon, Rick.
We're -- We're almost there.
Ugh, leave me, Morty.
It's the only way.
Wha-- Were --
Wha-- Were we --
Were we Blades
in that one?
That's [bleep] tight.
Just stay with me.
[ Creature roars ]
I'm -- I'm scared,
Morty.
I can see the end.
I'm a silly man.
I'm a silly small man.
I'm -- I'm sorry
I got you into this.
Then how about
I get us outta this?
[ Alarm blaring ]
Hello?
Hey, Jessica.
I-It's Morty.
From school.
Oh, hey, Morty.
What's up?
Um, I just want to say
that you're really great.
I know the timing never really
worked out with us,
but you're really great and
I wish I got to know you better.
Oh, I mean --
That's a lot.
Oh, uh, yeah, sorry,
I guess I just --
No, I just wish
you said it sooner.
Wh-What?
Yeah, I mean,
being nervous
is sort of selfish
sometimes, y'know?
Life support systems failing.
Yeah,
that's a great point.
Well, what are you
doing tonight?
Tonight?
Yeah.
Do you, like, want to watch
a movie or something?
Um, yeah. Tonight.
Sounds great.
Holy [bleep]
Come on, come on!
[ Groans ] Oh.
Where are we?
We're home, Rick.
I-I landed us
in the ocean.
The ocean?!
The ocean on Earth?!
Uh, yeah, I-I guess so.
Oh [bleep]
Holy [bleep]
We have to go.
We have to go
right [bleep] now.
What?
You touched the ocean,
Morty.
What's the big --
Oh [bleep] [bleep]
What?
Richard!
You have desecrated
the sacred treaty
betwixt land
and sea.
Now face the wrath
of your once and eternal foe --
Mr. Nimbus!
Sorry.
Who is that?
My nemesis.
What?
My [bleep] nemesis,
okay?
Okay, but what was
his name again?
I am Mr. Nimbus!
He's gonna
say that a lot.
♪♪
[ Electricity crackles ]
W-Wait, so who is
coming over again?
He said his nemesis?
Rick has a nemesis?
I guess.
Has he
mentioned him before?
I-I was gonna ask you.
First I'm hearing it.
Who is he?
Like a magic guy?
Rick's science
and he's magic?
He's like a-a fish?
A fish.
He's not a fish.
He's Mr. Nimbus.
He's king of the ocean
and he's a piece of [bleep]
Are you happy, Morty?
Are you happy you
touched the ocean?
He's gonna be here
any minute.
Just help me
smooth this over
or this guy's gonna become
more trouble than he's worth.
Um, hey, I don't know how much
I can help out tonight, Rick.
Jessica's coming over
j-just to, like,
watch a movie
or something,
but y'know,
t-t-that's a good step.
That's a solid step
to something, y'know?
Truly nobody cares
about your [bleep] Morty.
The sooner you learn that,
the better.
I think you just don't
want me happy
'cause then I'll stop
doing your crazy chores.
Trust me,
after that ocean [bleep]up,
you don't get
to do anything crazy.
While I bull[bleep]
my way
through this peace summit treaty
with Nimbus,
Summer is gonna dive
into the Marianas Trench
to recover
the forbidden shell
that gives him
his power
because Summer
can be trusted.
Let's lick [bleep]
Okay, what?
I don't love that.
Of course you don't,
'cause you guys
aren't getting any.
[ Scoffs ] Actually,
your father and I
have been very
sex-positive lately.
Eww.
Dr. Wong suggested
we experiment.
We've been watching pornography.
Together.
Gross!
I might never come back
from the ocean.
Oh, you'll have to
tone it down, babe.
The squares
can't handle it.
[ Purrs ]
There are suicide capsules
in all of your teeth.
Do what you want
with that.
C'mon, Morty.
You're on booze duty.
Okay, Nimbus only drinks
the good [bleep]
So just toss this
whale-ass ocean-wine in here
and age it up
a few centuries.
So time moves faster
in there?
I-I-Is it like
a Narnia thing?
I'm not a beaver who believes
in Jesus Christ, Morty.
But yeah, it's pretty much
a Narnia thing.
Okay,
but Jessica --
All you have to do
is bring wine, Morty.
When do I ask you
for anything?
When do you --
I haven't been to
a full week of school in years!
I don't know shit!
And for what?
How many enemies
do you have to have?
Why is everything a fight
with you?
You might want to
learn this early, Morty.
Life is a fight.
With Mr. Nimbus?
Are you
makin' fun of me?
Mr. Nimbus is
an ice-cold dick killer, Morty.
[ Horn blows ]
Okay, let's go.
That's his magic ocean horn.
Is that Mr. Nimbus?
Nimbus.
Richard.
You look like ass.
Let's get this
over with.
I'm sorry.
This is the guy?
Jerry.
Hold on.
No.
I've seen you
[bleep] a planet,
and this is the guy
you're afraid of?
I like this one,
Rick.
He is unbroken.
Untamed.
Perhaps he could use
a firmer grip upon his leash.
Okay, that's enough.
I'm calling the police.
Go ahead.
Jerry.
I will!
Good.
I control them.
Excuse me?
He controls police,
Jerry.
Right,
that tracks.
In Dumb World.
Police?
A strange horny ocean man
is on my lawn.
Well, I don't see
how that's relevant,
but we're white.
[ Sirens wail, tires screech ]
Freeze!   Freeze!
Freeze!         Freeze!
Fight.
[ All grunting ]
[Bleep]
[ All moaning ]
Flee.
Officer:
Let's get outta here.
[ Sirens wail, tires squeal ]
Shall we, Richard?
Okay,
but how did he --
Jesus Christ, Jerry. He's Mr.
Nimbus. He controls the police!
Um, hello?
Am I in the right place?
I just saw a bunch of cops
having sex with each other?
Hi! Jessica! Hi!
Yeah, yup, y-you're
in the right spot.
Uh, everyone,
th-this is Jessica.
This is everybody.
Uh, this is --
I am Mr. Nimbus.
Jesus, Nimbus,
just get inside.
Morty,
grab the wine.
Yeah, in a minute.
C-C'mon, Jessica.
Stand aside.
Unless you are
worthy of Nimbus.
[ Scoffs ] If that means
what I think it means,
I'll have you know,
we watch porn together.
Oh!
Ooh!
Wow, okay! Looks like you guys
just got the nod.
The nod?
Mr. Nimbus
has a sense for these things.
I take it you're
a sex-positive couple?
Oh, yeah.
Very much so.
We watch porn together.
Great!
I'll mark you down
as eligible for a threeway.
Here's all the information
you'll need.
The king of the ocean wants
to have a threesome with us?
Totally optional.
But a remarkable option to have,
I assure you. Very jealous.
There's a form
on the last page
so we know where to send
the gift basket.
So that just happened.
You don't sound
upset about it.
Neither do you.
Oh, my God.
Is this happening? To us?
I thought this only happened
in New York or on HBO.
Dr. Wong
hasn't been wrong yet.
You're right.
This is exactly
what she was talking about.
So, uh, yeah. J-Just make
yourself comfortable.
Y'know, ch-choose a movie or --
or we can watch
some interdimensional cable
if you want.
We now return to "Nintendo 69."
Nintendo, oh,
what are you doing to me?
Oh, Nintendo, oh, Nin--
Or we can watch whatever,
y'know.
Wh-Whatever you're into.
Morty, did I hear
you're getting wine?
Yeah, I gotta get some wine
for Mr. Nimbus.
Got any extra?
Oh.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, I'll go get some,
just for you.
Cool.
Hurry back.
Looks like
you could use a hand.
Oh, hey!
Yeah, th-th-that'd be great.
No problem.
Hoovy?
Dinner's ready!
Be right there,
sugar hoof!
Just helping this young man
through a portal
with that
crate full of alcohol
that's been here
for decades.
Hey, thanks, Hoovy.
I-I really appreciate that.
I-I got a girl over,
and I really, really like her.
I-I'm just nervous.
Oh, I know that feeling.
When I first started
seeing Bova,
I could only think about all
the ways I was gonna mess it up.
So what'd you do?
Oh, I messed it up.
[ Chuckles ]
But I found the one
who loves me for that.
Thanks.
I-I really needed to hear that.
Here,
t-take one of these.
Oh, you don't have to.
No, I-I want to.
You have a good day, Hoovy.
You have a great time
with that lady up there.
Just relax.
Will do!
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Bova?
[ Gasps ]
Why did you leave us,
Father?
Japheth?
When were you born?
[ Grunts ]
I swore to Mother
if I ever met you,
I'd avenge her.
It wasn't my fault.
Whose, then?
Whose?!
The boy
from the magic door.
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Shall we
discuss terms?
Yeah, fine.
Whatever. Terms.
Term number one --
I am King of the Ocean.
The place I shit?
Go ahead.
Term number two --
Stop shitting in the ocean.
No idea [burps]
what you're talking about.
Delicious. Another.
Oh, uh, well, I-I was thinking
of using this one for --
Morty, just give him the bottle.
God damn.
Another!
Morty,
you get the wine?
Hey, Jessica.
Um, yeah, sorry.
I just -- just going back
to get it.
Oh.
I thought you already went.
I did! I just --
just got a little busy.
Going right now,
again!
You go ahead
and fire up that movie!
That's okay.
I'll wait for you.
Holy shit, holy shit,
holy shit, holy shit!
♪♪
I've been waiting
for you.
Oh, wow.
Hoovy, right?
Never say his name!
[ Grunts ]
Jesus Christ!
Why -- Why is every old guy
super jacked?
[ Grunts ]
Sorry!
I'm sorry!
I-I just need the wine!
I'm sorry! Stop it!
[Bleep] kill you!
Ow!
Okay, screw this!
[ Groans ]
You know what?
You!
Yeah [bleep] you,
Hoovy!
[ Groans ]
Father?
It's him!
I told you he'd come back!
Holy [bleep]
Okay, look, he wasn't old
like 10 seconds ago.
[ Grunts ]
Ow! Mother[bleep]!
[ Groans ]
I'm sorry, Father.
I'm sorry we never believed.
He'll come back.
Stop him.
♪♪
Papa,
why do we guard the gate?
Because one day,
the dark child shall return.
And we will be ready.
[ Thunder rumbles ]
Delicious.
Where is your wine boy, Richard?
I thirst.
He's getting it.
Stop eating beignets like that.
Participant voids
all liability
in the event
of death by orgasm?
Are we really ready
to open things this wide?
What if
it gets weird?
I fall in love with him?
No, no, no, no, no.
Damn it!
What was that?
Another scheme of yours,
Richard?
I know you're
planning something.
It's nothing.
Will you excuse me, please?
What the [bleep] is going on?
Where's the wine?
Dad was horny
and I dropped it.
God, I can't -- I can't believe
you're [bleep] this up.
I'm not [bleep] it up! There was
a guy in the thing and --
There's always a guy
in a thing!
Nimbus: Land dwellers do not
keep Nimbus waiting and live.
Be right out!
Goddammit.
Do you see this whisper kitchen
"Frasier" bull[bleep]
you're making me do?
Morty, just get the wine.
Beth and Jerry,
stop trying to [bleep] Nimbus.
Well,
we wouldn't do it here.
I'll have you know
he propositioned us.
He propositions everybody!
Hey, hey, hey,
Jessica.
W-What's up?
Seems like you're busy.
No, no, no!
I ran into a little trouble.
But -- But -- But I'll go get
that wine right now.
But you said were going to
get it like twice already.
I-I-I was
and I-I'm getting it right now.
[ Grunts ]
Holy [bleep] it's him!
[ Trumpet blows ]
God damn it!
What do you want me to say?!
I-I'm sorry!
♪♪
[ Cheering ]
We finally beat him.
But let's always
remain vigilant
because you never know.
He might be back
one day.
Okay, Narnia!
Let's go.
Let's [bleep] go!
It is over.
The boy is not coming back.
He always comes back.
You have wasted
our lives,
our very futures,
on a fantasy!
A lie!
I know what I saw.
You saw nothing!
You are
a foolish boy!
♪♪
Those called fools
are the only ones brave enough
to see the truth.
♪♪
[ Grunts ]
[ All gasp ]
♪♪
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Groans ]
Tell me, Father.
Am I a fool now?
[ Grunts ]
♪♪
[ Groans ]
I was born in the pits
that made these stones.
I lost my years
building a temple to a lie.
So I made lies
my power.
And what is power
but a lie we --
Aah!
Oh [bleep] he's real!
He's real!
I was wrong!
I was so wrong!
God is real!
[ Gunfire, screaming ]
♪♪
Wow.
Impeccable service.
Big tip.
I liked
your other one more.
What was his name?
Kyle?
What?
Nothing.
Can we just
sign this thing and go?
Jessica,
I-I'm so sorry.
I mean, it's fine.
You were only gone
like a couple minutes.
Morty,
are you okay?
I'm -- I'm sorry,
Jessica.
We just never seem
to get it right, do we?
No, I guess we don't.
[ Chuckles ]
But I'm glad
you called me.
Maybe we can start over,
get it right this time.
Yeah.
I'd -- I'd like that.
♪♪
Thanks for
bringing the wine.
Totally worth it.
Do we need
an opener?
Oh.
I'll -- I'll -- I'll go get it.
Nimbus: Mmm.
I do so love to sign
upon the dotted line.
Shall we?
Jesus Christ,
yes.
And who
is your witness?
My witness
is the squid.
Really proud of this
SeaWorld theme, aren't you?
Hey, just get a witness, man.
Don't make this about me.
Or perhaps
Richard has no one
with whom
he can trust his life.
Who truly knows him.
Save me.
Fine!
I'll get someone.
Oh, my God.
Morty! C'mere.
I need you for some bull[bleep]
Look, Rick, I've done
everything you've asked.
Now can I just have some time
with my girlfriend?
Your girlfriend?
I mean, she's not --
we kissed,
but I'm just trying
to take it slow.
You gotta give these things
time to breathe, y'know?
♪♪
Do you know why
you're special, Adam?
Because I am
The Traveler?
Yes.
You will be the one
to pass through the door.
to end our pain.
But, Mother,
what about my pain?
Your pain
shall set us free.
It is time to begin.
[ Warbling ]
[ Grunting ]
Again.
Again!
[ Grunting ]
You are not ready.
Please, Mother --
Do you think
he will show you mercy?
Like he did to us?
Again!
♪♪
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasps ]
Does anyone
need anything?
Does Nimbus
Holy [bleep]
Don't judge.
We're growing
as a couple!
Aah!
Why is this happening
to me?!
For the future!
♪♪
You dare
assassinate Nimbus?
Sorry. Wait.
Who -- Who is that?
Get in line,
pal!
[ Grunts ]
[ Screams ]
♪♪
Such a waste.
M-Mother?
[ Screeches ]
Aah!
[ Screams ]
Jessica!
You just had
to touch the ocean.
Aaah!
Shut up!
There isn't time to --
It's all [bleep]
and you [bleep] it!
[ Screaming ]
Huh?
You're early.
W-What is this place?
The end.
But also a beginning.
Isn't every end
a beginning?
Stay back!
I don't want your stripped down
Sundance sci-fi bullshit.
Where's Jessica?
Jessica.
That was her name, wasn't it?
Thank you, Morty.
I had forgotten.
Oh, right.
You'll be needing this.
For the wine.
♪♪
[ Grunts ]
Oh [bleep] we got him!
Can you believe he bought
that [bleep] tree bull[bleep]?
We [bleep] got him!
Very well.
If you seek war with Atlantis,
you shall have it.
Oh, I've already been to war
with Atlantis
when I D-Day'd
that Mermaid [bleep]
I knew
that was you!
Prepare my exit parade!
Say goodbye
to your precious dry land!
For soon it will be wet!
Wet!
Yeah, global warming
is already doing that, asshole.
But sure, yeah, go for it.
Make us slightly more wet!
Am I a joke
to you?
Yes,
you are a [bleep] joke!
You [bleep] suck!
You've always sucked!
Y-Y-Y know why
we haven't fought in years?
'Cause you're an embarrassment
to me
and I don't need you
anymore.
I don't need anybody.
All I do is eat [bleep]
and 69 Nintendos, bro.
Every day.
Or maybe you hate me
because I am the only man
to see how far you have fallen.
I used to fear you.
Respect you.
Now all that's left
is pity --
for a sad, drunk shell
of a man
too afraid to see
how alone he truly is.
If Diane were alive today,
what would she think --
Don't [bleep] establish
canonical backstory with
me, you Red Lob--
[ Gasps ]
Oh, good.
You're awake.
I just
took some wine!
I said I was sorry.
What the [bleep]
is wrong with you people?!
I have been asking that
for centuries.
I was created to study you,
Morty, to know you.
But the closer
I looked,
the more I do not
recognize myself.
Uh, yeah, man, I really don't
have time for --
I have often wondered who
would we be without you, Morty?
Are we anything
beyond our hatred?
And when she came,
I thought
she would be the answer.
Frozen in time.
Forever asleep.
We could not understand
her purpose,
so we hid her away.
Why do we always hide
the truths we fear?
[ Groans ]
I don't
give a [bleep] nerd!
Let her go!
Why -- Why did
I clone myself genitals?
Ow!
I don't care, bitch!
Do it!
Ooh! Asshole!
Yeah,
guess I am an asshole!
Y'know, sometimes you gotta be
an asshole!
My grandpa
taught me that!
Okay, okay, okay,
fine!
[ Groans ]
♪♪
Morty?
Hey, Jessica.
Wow.
Must've been some nap, huh?
I-Is that ooze or --
I'm not sure what to call it.
It l-l-looks like ooze.
Okay.
W-We can catch up later.
♪♪
[ Screeches ]
What the --
[ Gasps ]
Rick! Rick!
...obster mother[bleep]
Morty: Rick!
Screw this.
What am I even doing?
Help!
Where are you?
Come back here.
I'm going to make the land wet!
Y'know what,
I'd love to see it.
Do it!
God, do anything!
Just don't use me
as an excuse anymore!
Rick!
Wow.
That was intense.
You look stressed.
We signed
the paperwork.
I must go.
Well, your people
have our number!
Your starfish mentioned
some kind of basket?
Jesus, Morty.
Stop! No, no!
Not today!
Can't you go one day
without --
You don't get to --
What the --
I [bleep] it up, okay?
It's okay, Morty.
That's what you do.
Now lemme Deus Ex Machina
this [bleep] and let's go home.
♪♪
God, why does everyone go
Cyber-Punk Bird?
So [bleep] hack.
♪♪
Oh [bleep]
Well, that's cool.
♪♪
Okay, we might be
a little [bleep]
[ Horn blows ]
Did you think I would
let you die alone, Richard?
[ Grunting ]
♪♪
I am Mr. Nimbus!
Wow. Phew.
You -- You still got time
for that movie?
Yes. Time.
I had nothing
but time.
Endless time.
At first,
it was madness.
Then enlightenment.
Then madness again.
But perhaps
it was a gift.
I could see
the life of time.
And as I watched
the life of time
in all its fleeting,
terrible light,
I wondered,
had I lived?
Was I just the object
in another's story?
Was that all I ever was?
Could I be more?
I had nothing but time
and still no answer.
Time without purpose
is a prison.
I have glimpsed into the mind
of eternity.
Perhaps the mind of God.
And found
nothing but silence.
I think we should
just be friends.
Oh, yeah.
I-I-I get that.
Guess we missed
our moment.
Yes.
But there will be more.
For both of us.
Goodbye, Morty.
Hey,
how's it going?
[Bleep] off!
I'm a Time-god!
Fighting by your side again,
Richard.
It was, uh --
Yeah.
Then there is
no treaty.
Because there is
no war.
Aw, Nimbus.
That's --
That's really chill of you, man.
Richard.
Before you were
my greatest enemy,
you were
my only friend.
Grandpa,
I got the shell!
[Bleep]
Okay, Nimbus, look.
You son of a bitch!
Betrayal!
My weapons, Morty!
I-I-I used them all!
Grandpa!
Wait, Grandpa,
what do I do?
I have the shell.
Should I blow it?
Is that -- I'm --
I'm just gonna blow it!
Don't blow it!
Destroy the horn!
What the hell,
Summer?!
You were supposed to
destroy the horn!
How was I
supposed to know that?
[ Groans ]
[ Siren wails ]
Nimbus: Police!
Take this piece of [bleep]
to jail.
I told, ugh, I told you.
He's an ice-cold
dick killer!
Nimbus!
[ Tires squeal ]
Wait.
So how can he --
Jesus, Summer.
He's Mr. Nimbus.
He controls the police!
♪♪
Jer, I think
more than one safe word
sort of
defeats the point.
I know,
I just wanna make sure
we have
every opportunity to stop.
Super excited
about it though.
Me too, so excited.
Jerry, are we doing this
because we both want this?
Or because it's what we think
the other one wants?
I just wanted to prove
that I love you so much
I would do this
for you!
Same!
Let's take that prize
and get out
before we make
a huge mistake.
Getting cold feet?
No.
Please don't tell Rick.
He wouldn't understand.
Yes, he would.