CREAK
Run.
- I'm The Doctor, by the way. What's your name?
- Rose.
- Nice to meet you.
Run for your life.
It'll follow us!
The hordes of Genghis Khan couldn't get through
that door. Believe me, they tried.
Are you alien? Yes.
You could come with me.
Is it always this dangerous? Yeah.
Right, Rose Tyler, you tell me -
where do you wanna go? Backwards
or forwards in time? Your choice.
What's it gonna be?
Forwards.
How far? ...One hundred years.
TARDIS REVS AND GROANS
Step outside those doors - it's
the 22nd century. You're kidding.
That's a bit boring, though.
D'you wanna go further? Fine by me.
Ten thousand years in the future.
Step outside - it's the year 12005.
The new Roman Empire.
You think you're so impressive.
I am so impressive. You wish!
Right, then. You asked for it.
I know exactly where to go.
Hold on!
TARDIS GROANS AND ROARS
PING!
Where are we?
FAINT CREAKS
What's out there?
You lot... you spend all your time
thinking about dying.
Like you're gonna get killed
by eggs or beef
or global warming or asteroids.
But you never take time to imagine
the impossible,
that maybe you survive.
This is the year 5.5/Apple/26.
Five billion years in your future.
And this is the day...
Hold on...
This is the day the sun expands.
Welcome to the end of the world.
Shuttles five and six now docking.
Guests are reminded
that Platform One forbids the use of
weapons, teleportation and religion.
Earth-death is scheduled for 15:39,
followed by drinks in the Manchester Suite.
So when it says "guests",
does that mean people?
Depends what you mean by people.
I mean people. What do you mean?
Aliens. What are they doing on board
this space-ship? What's it all for?
It's not really a spaceship,
more like an observation deck.
The great and the good are gathering
to watch the planet burn. What for?
Fun.
Mind you, when I say "the great and
the good" what I mean is the rich.
But, hold on, they did this once on
Newsround Extra, the sun expanding,
it takes hundreds of years. Millions.
But the planet's now the property
of the National Trust.
They've been keeping it preserved.
See down there? Gravity satellites
holding back the sun.
The planet looks
the same as ever. I thought
the continents shifted and things.
They did. The Trust moved 'em back.
That's a Classic Earth. Now the
money's run out, nature takes over.
How long's it got?
About half an hour.
Then the planet gets roasted.
Is that why we're here?
I mean, is that what you do?
Jump in at the last
minute and save the Earth?
I'm not saving it. Time's up.
But what about the people? It's
empty. They've all gone. All left.
Just me, then.
Who the hell are you?
Oh, that's nice. Thanks(!)
But how did you get in?
This is a maximum hospitality zone,
the guests have disembarked. They're
on their way! Any second now...
No, that's me, I'm a guest. Look,
I've got an invitation. Look. Y'see?
It's fine. "The Doctor plus one".
I'm the Doctor, this is Rose Tyler,
she's my plus one. That all right?
Well, obviously.
Apologies, et cetera.
If you're on board,
we'd better start.
Enjoy.
The paper's slightly psychic. It
shows whatever I want them to see.
Saves a lot of time.
He's blue. Yeah... OK.
We have in attendance the Doctor
and Rose Tyler. Thank you.
All staff to their positions!
Hurry now! Thank you! Quick as
we can, come along, come along!
And now, might I introduce
the next honoured guest?
Representing the Forest of Cheam
we have trees,
namely Jabe, Lute and Coffa.
There will be an exchange of gifts
representing peace. If you could keep
the room circulating, thank you...
Next, from the solicitors Jolco &
Jolco, we have the Moxx of Balhoon.
And next,
from Financial Family Seven,
we have
the Adherents of the Repeated Meme.
The inventors of hyposlip travel
systems, the brothers Hop Pyleen!
..Cal "Spark" Plug... Mrs and Mrs
Pacoon... The ambassadors from
the City-State of Binding Light...
A gift of peace. I bring you
a cutting of my grandfather.
Thank you, yes...
Gifts, um...
Ahem! I give you in return...
air from my lungs.
How... intimate.
There's more where that came from.
I bet there is.
..Our friend from
the Silver Devastation, the sponsor
of the main event, please welcome...
..the Face of Boe.
The Moxx of Balhoon.
My felicitations
upon this historical happenstance.
I bring the gift of bodily salivas.
HAWKS AND SPITS
Thank you very much.
Ah, the Adherents of the Repeated
Meme! I bring you air from my lungs.
A gift of peace. In all good faith.
..And last but not least,
our very special guest.
Ladies and gentlemen
and trees and multiforms,
consider the Earth, below.
In memory of this dying world,
we call forth...
the Last Human.
The Lady Cassandra O'Brien Dot Delta
Seventeen.
Oh, now don't stare! I know,
I know - it's shocking, isn't it?
I've had my chin completely taken
away, and look at the difference,
look how thin I am!
Thin and dainty!
I don't look a day over 2, 000.
(Moisturise me, moisturise me!)
Truly, I am the Last Human.
My father was a Texan, my
mother was from the Arctic Desert.
They were born on the Earth,
and they were the last to be buried
in its soil.
I have come to honour them...
HER VOICE BREAKS
..and say goodbye.
Oh, no tears, no tears...
I'm sorry.
But behold!
I bring gifts!
>From Earth itself,
the last remaining ostrich egg.
Legend says
it had a wing-span of 50 feet
and blew fire from its nostrils.
Or was that my THIRD husband?
Oh, no, oh, don't laugh,
I'll get laughter-lines. No, stop!
SHE GIGGLES
Mercy!
And here! Another rarity.
According to the archives,
this was called an iPod,
it stores classical music from
humanity's greatest composers.
Play on!
INTRO TO "Tainted Love" by Soft Cell
The refreshments will now be served.
Earth-death in 30 minutes.
MARC ALMOND:
# Sometimes I feel I've got to
Run away
# I've got to
Get away... #
POLITE CHAT
#... The love we share
Seems to go nowhere
# And I've lost my light
# For I toss and turn
I can't sleep at night... #
Doctor.
Thank you.
A gift of peace.
In all good faith.
Er, no, you're very kind,
but I'm just the steward.
A gift of PEACE.
In all good FAITH.
Oh... yes. Thank you.
Of course.
Identify species.
Please identify species.
IT WHISTLES
Now stop it! Identify his race.
Where's he from?
IT WHISTLES AND TRILLS
It's impossible.
Sorry, am I allowed to be in 'ere?
..You have to give us
permission to talk.
Um...
Y-You have permission.
Thank you.
And, no, you're not in the way.
Guests are allowed anywhere. Oh.
BUTTONS BLEEP
What's your name?
Raffalo.
Raffalo?
Yes, miss.
I... I won't be long I've just got
to carry out some maintenance.
There's a tiny little glitch
in the Face of Boe's suite.
There must be something blocking
the system. He's getting no hot
water. So... you're a plumber?
That's right miss.
They still have plumbers?
I hope so, else I'm out of a job!
Where are you from? Crespallion.
That's a planet, is it?
No, Crespallion's part
of the Jaggit Brocade affiliated
to the Scarlet Junction. Convex 56.
And where are you from, miss?
If you don't mind my asking?
No, not at all...
Um, I dunno
A long way away.
I just sort of hitched a lift
with this man...
I didn't even think about it.
Don't even know who he is.
He's a complete stranger.
Anyway, um, don't let me keep you.
Good luck with it!
Thank you, miss. And, er...
thank you for the permission. Not
many people are that considerate.
OK... See you later.
Now, then.
Control, I'm at junction 19. I think
the problem's coming from in here.
I'll go inside and have a look.
IRREGULAR CLICKS
What's that?
Is there something in there?
Ooh, who are you, then?
Hold on!
If you're an upgrade,
I just need to register you,
that's all. Oh, come back.
Ah, there you are.
Now, I just need to register
your ident.
Aw, there's two of ya!
Got yourself a little mate?
MORE AND MORE CLICKS
I think I'd better report this to
control. How many of you ARE there?
What are you?
Oh, no!
NO! NO-O-O!
MUTED BLEEPS
What's that?
MORE BLEEPS
Well, how should I know?
PING!
Would the owner of the blue box
in Private Gallery 15
please report to
the steward's office immediately.
Guests are reminded that
the use of teleportation
devices is strictly forbidden
under peace treaty 5.4/cup/16.
Thank you.
'Earth-death in 25 minutes.
'Earthdeath in 25 minutes.'
Oh, thanks.
Hello!
My name's Rose.
That's a... sort of plant.
We might be related.
I'm talking to a twig.
Oi now, careful with that,
park it properly. No scratches.
ALIEN LANGUAGE
Rose, are you in there?
Aye-aye!
What d'you think, then? Great, yeah.
Fine. Once you get past
the slightly psychic paper.
They're just so alien!
The aliens are so alien.
You look at 'em...
and they're alien.
Good thing I didn't take you
to the deep South(!)
Where are you from?
All over the place.
They all speak English. No,
you just hear English. It's a gift
of the Tardis. Telepathic field,
gets inside your brain, translates.
It's inside MY brain?
Well, in a good way.
Your machine gets inside my head?
It gets inside and it changes
my mind, and you didn't even ask?
I didn't think about it like that.
No, you were too busy thinking up
cheap shots about the deep South!
Who are YOU, then, Doctor? What're
you called? What sort of alien
are you? I'm just the Doctor.
>From what planet? It's not as if
you'd know it where it is(!) Where
are you from? What's it matter?
Tell me who you are! THIS is who
I am, right here, right now,
all right? All that counts
is here and now. And this is me.
Yes, and I'm here too, cos you
brought me here. So just tell me!
'Earth-death in 20 minutes,
'Earth-death in 20 minutes.'
All right.
As my mate Shireen says, don't argue
with the designated driver.
Can't exactly call for a taxi.
No signal.
We're out of range. Just a bit.
Tell you what. With a little bit
of jiggery-pokery... Is that a
technical term, jiggery-pokery(?)
Yes, I came first in jiggery-pokery.
What about you?
No, failed hullabaloo. Aw.
There you go.
PHONE RINGS AT OTHER END
Hello? Mum? Oh, what is it?
What's wrong, what have I done now?
Ooh, this red top's falling to bits!
You should get your money back.
Go on, there must be something.
You never phone in the middle
of the day... What's so funny?
Nothing. You all right, though?
Yeah, why wouldn't I be?
What day is it? Wednesday all day.
You got a hangover?
Ooh, I tell you what, put a quid
in that lottery syndicate. I'll pay
you back later. Yeah, um, I...
I was just calling cos... I might
be late home. Is there something
wrong? No, I'm fine.
Top of the world!
Think THAT'S amazing,
you wanna see the bill.
That was five billion years ago.
So...
She's dead now.
Five billion years later,
my mum's dead.
Bundle of laughs, you are.
BIG RUMBLE
That's not supposed to happen.
Well, what was it? I'm just
getting green lights at this end.
Honoured guests may be reassured
that gravity pockets may cause
slight turbulence. Thanking you...
The whole place shook! I felt it!
I've hosted all sorts of events
on platforms 1, 3, 6 and 15 and
never felt the slightest tremor.
I warn you, if this lot decide
to sue...!
I'm gonna scan the infrastructure.
CLICKS AND SQUEAKS
What's that?
Control, I don't want to worry you
but I'm picking up readings...
I have no idea! They're small.
The scan says they're metal...
I don't know what they look like!
Although I imagine they might look
rather like that.
You're not on the guest list.
How did you get on board?
No! 'Sunfilter deactivated.'
No!
'Sunfilter descending.' No!
Sunfilter up!
No, no, no!
Control! Respond!
'Sunfilter descending.'
SUNFILTER UP!
'Sunfilter descending... '
HE SCREAMS
Indubitably, this is the Bad-Boo
scenario. I find the inherent laxity
of the unknown multiverse...
That wasn't a gravity pocket, I know
gravity pockets, and they don't feel
like that... What d'you think, Jabe?
Listen to the engines.
They've pitched up about 30 hertz.
Is that dodgy or what?!
It's the sound of metal - it doesn't
make any sense to me. Where's
the engine room? I don't know.
But the maintenance duct
is just behind our guest suite.
I could show you. And... your wife.
Oh, she's not my wife.
Partner? No. Concubine?
Nope.
Prostitute? Whatever I am,
it must be invisible(!) D'you mind?!
Tell you what, you two go...
pollinate. I'll catch up with family.
Quick word with Michael Jackson.
Don't start a fight.
I'm all yours.
And I want you home by midnight.
'Earth-death in 15 minutes.
Earth-death in 15 minutes.'
Who's in charge of Platform One?
Has it got a captain or what?
There's just the steward and staff.
All the rest is controlled by the
metalmind. You mean the computer?
Well, who controls that?
The Corporation.
They move Platform One
from one artistic event to another.
There's no-one from the corporation
on board? They're not needed.
This facility is purely automatic.
It's the height of the Alpha Class.
Nothing can go wrong. Unsinkable(?)
If you like. The nautical metaphor
is appropriate.
You're telling me! I was on board
another ship they called unsinkable.
I ended up clinging to an iceberg.
Wasn't half cold.
So what you're saying is
if we get in trouble,
there's no-one to help us out.
I'm afraid not. Fantastic!
I don't understand.
In what way is that fantastic?
Soon the sun
will blossom into a red giant
And my home will die.
That's where I used to live,
when I was a little boy. Down there.
Mummy and Daddy had a house built
into the side of the Los Angeles
Crevasse. Ah, I'd have such fun.
What happened to everyone else?
The human race, where did it go?
They say mankind has touched
every star in the sky.
So you're not the last human.
I am the Last Pure Human.
The others... mingled.
Oh, they call themselves
New Humans and Protohumans and
Digihumans - even Human-ish -
but d'you know what I call them?
Mongrels.
Right(!) And you stayed behind.
I kept myself pure.
How many operations have you had?
708. Next week, it's 709.
I'm having my blood bleached.
Is that why you wanted a word?
You could be flatter, Rose.
You've got a little bit
of a... chin poking out.
I'd rather die.
Honestly, it doesn't hurt.
I mean it. I would rather die.
It's better to die than to live
like you, a bitchy trampoline.
Oh, well, what do YOU know?
I was born on that planet.
And so was my mum, and so was my dad,
and that makes me, officially,
the last human being in this room.
Cos you're not human. You've had it
all nipped and tucked and flattened
till there's nothing left.
Anything human got chucked
in the bin. You're just skin,
Cassandra, lipstick and skin.
Nice talking.
So, tell me, Jabe,
what's a tree like you
doing in a place like this?
Respect for the Earth.
Oh, come on, everyone on
this Platform's worth zillions.
Well. Perhaps it's a case of having
to be seen at the right occasions.
In case your share prices drop?
I know you lot, you've got massive
forests, roots everywhere.
And there's always money in land.
All the same, we respect the Earth
as family.
So many species evolved from
that planet. Mankind is only one.
I'm another. My ancestors were
transplanted from the planet down
below, and I'm a direct descendant
of the tropical rainforest.
Excuse me.
And what about your ancestry,
Doctor?
Perhaps you could tell
a story or two.
Perhaps a man only enjoys trouble
when there's nothing else left...?
I scanned you earlier.
The metalmachine had trouble
identifying your species.
It refused to admit your existence.
And even when it named you,
I wouldn't believe it.
But it was right.
I know where you're from!
Forgive me for intruding, but
it's remarkable that you even exist.
I just want to say...
how sorry I am.
SLOW CHUFFING
Is it me, or is it a bit nippy?
SHE CRIES OUT
Fair do's though - that's a great
bit of air-conditioning. Sort of
nice and old-fashioned.
Bet they call it retro.
Gotcha.
What the hell's that?
Is it part of the "retro"?
I don't think so, hold on.
Hey, nice liana. Thank you.
Not supposed to show them in public.
Don't worry, I won't tell anybody.
Now then, who's been bringing their
pets on board? What does it do?
Sabotage...
'Earth-death in ten minutes... '
And the temperature's
about to rocket. Come on.
'... Earth death in ten minutes.'
The planet's end!
Come gather, come gather!
Bid farewell to the cradle
of civilisation.
Let us mourn her
with a traditional ballad.
INTRO TO: "Toxic"
sung by Britney Spears
# Baby, can't you see
I'm calling
# A guy like you
Should wear a warning
# It's dangerous
I'm fallin'... #
SQUEAKS AND TRILLS
All right, hold on, get back.
'Sunfilter rising.
Sunfilter rising.'
Is the Steward in there?
You can smell him.
Hold on. There's another sunfilter
programmed to descend.
#... Too high
Can't come down
# Losing my head
Spinning round and round
# Do you feel me now...? #
'Sunfilter descending.
Sunfilter descending... '
'Sunfilter descending... '
Let me out! Let me out!
'... Sunfilter descending... '
LOUD BANGING
Let me out! Let me out!
'... Sunfilter descending.
Sunfilter descending... '
MORE BANGING
Anyone in there?
Let me out! Oh, well,
it would be you(!) Open the door!
Give us two ticks...
'... Sunfilter descending.
Sunfilter descending... '
'Sunfilter rising. Sunfilter rising.
'Sunfilter rising.
Sunfilter rising... '
'... Sunfilter rising.
'Sunfilter descending... '
Just what we need -
the computer's getting clever.
Stop mucking about! I'm not mucking
about! It's fighting back.
'... Sunfilter descending... '
Open the door! I know!
The lock's melted!
'... Sunfilter descending.
Sunfilter descending.
'Sunfilter rising.
Sunfilter rising... '
The whole thing's
jammed. I can't open the door.
Stay there, don't move.
Where am I gonna go - Ipswich(?)
'Earth-death in five minutes.'
The metalmachine confirms.
The spider devices have infiltrated
the whole of Platform One.
How's that possible? Our private
rooms are protected by a codewall.
(Moisturise me, moisturise me!)
Summon the Steward! I'm afraid the
Steward is dead.
THEY GASP AND MURMUR
Who killed him?
This whole event was sponsored
by the Face of Boe. He invited us.
Talk to the Face, talk to the Face!
Easy way of finding out. Someone
brought their little pet on board.
Let's send him back to master.
The Adherents of the Repeated Meme!
J'accuse!
That's all very well,
and really kind of obvious but,
if you stop and think about it...
A repeated meme is just an idea.
And that's all they are, an idea.
Remote-control 'droids. Nice little
cover for the real troublemaker.
Go on, Jimbo. Go home.
GUESTS GASP
I bet you were the school swot
and never got kissed.
At arms!
What you gonna do, moisturise me?
With acid.
Oh, you're too late, anyway.
My spiders have control
of the mainframe.
Oh, you all carried them as gifts,
tax-free, past every codewall.
I'm not just a pretty face.
Sabotaging a ship while you're
inside it, how stupid's that?
I'd hoped to manufacture
a hostage situation.
With myself as one of the victims,
the compensation
would have been enormous.
Five billion years,
and it still comes down to money.
D'you think it's cheap,
looking like this?
Flatness costs a fortune!
I am the Last Human, Doctor.
Me, not that freaky little kid
of yours.
Arrest her! The infidel!
Oh, shut it, pixie!
I've still got my final option.
'Earth-death in three minutes,
Earth-death in three minutes... '
And here it comes. You're
just as useful dead, all of you.
I have shares in
your rival companies. They'll triple
in price as soon as you're dead.
My spiders are primed and ready
to destroy the safety systems.
How did that old Earth song go?
"Burn baby, burn."
Then you'll burn with us!
Oh, I'm so sorry!
I know the use of teleportation is
strictly forbidden, but...
I'm such a naughty thing.
Spiders, activate!
THUNDEROUS WHOOSHES
Force-fields gone,
with the planet about to explode...
At least it'll be quick.
Just like my fifth husband... Oops!
Oh, shame on me! Bye bye, darlings.
'Safety systems failing... '
Bye-bye, my darlings!
'... Heat levels rising... '
Reset the computer!
Only the Steward would know how.
No, we can do it by hand.
There must be a "system restore"
switch. Jabe, come on.
You lot, just chill.
'... Heat levels rising... '
'Earthdeath in two minutes.
Earthdeath in two minutes.'
'Heat levels critical,
heat levels critical.'
'... Heat levels rising.
Heat levels rising.'
Oh, and guess where the switch is(!)
'... Heat levels rising.
Heat levels rising.'
External temperature
5, 000 degrees.
You can't, the heat's gonna vent
through this place. I know. Jabe!
You're made of wood. Then stop
wasting time - Time Lord.
'Heat levels rising...
'Heat levels rising.'
'... Heat levels hazardous... '
We're going to die!
'Shields malfunction...
'Shields malfunction.
Shields malfunction.
'Shields malfunction... '
'Heat levels critical...
Heat levels critical.'
'Heat levels rising.
Heat levels rising.'
JABE SCREAMS
SCREAMS STOP
'Planet explodes in...
'... ten,
nine...
eight...
..seven...
..six...
..five...
fou... four...
Raise shields!
..one.
'Exoglass repair.
Exoglass repair... '
HE MURMURS
You all right? Yeah, I'm fine.
I'm full of ideas.
I'm bristling with 'em!
Idea number one.
Teleportation through 5, 000 degrees
needs some kind of feed.
Idea number two.
This feed must be hidden nearby.
Idea number three.
If you're as clever as me, then a
teleportation-feed can be reversed.
..Oh, you should've seen
their little alien faces...
Oh.
The last human. So.
You passed my little test. Bravo!
This makes you eligible to join, um,
the... the Human Club.
People have died, Cassandra.
You murdered them. It depends
on your definition of people.
And that's enough of a technicality
to keep your lawyers dizzy
for centuries.
Take me to court then, Doctor,
and watch me smile and cry...
QUIET CREAKS
..and flutter. And creak?
And what? Creak. You're creaking.
What?
Agh! I-I'm drying out!
Oh, sweet heavens!
Moisturise me, moisturise me!
Where are my surgeons,
my lovely boys? It's too hot!
YOU raised the temperature.
Have pity!
SHE GROWLS:
Moisturise me!
Oh, Doctor!
Oh, Doctor, I'll do anything...!
Help her. Everything has its time.
And everything dies.
I'm... too... young...!
'Shuttles four and six departing.
'This unit now closing
down for maintenance.'
The end of the Earth.
It's gone.
We were too busy saving ourselves.
No-one saw it go.
All those years, all that history,
and no-one was even looking.
It's just...
Come with me.
A TODDLER CRIES
Big Issue!
Big Issue...!
You think it'll last forever,
people and cars and concrete.
But it won't.
One day, it's all gone.
Even the sky.
My planet's gone.
It's dead.
It burned, like the Earth.
It's just rocks and dust.
Before its time.
What happened?
There was a war, and we lost.
A war with who?
What about your people?
I'm a Time Lord.
I'm the last of the Time Lords.
They're all gone.
I'm the only survivor.
I'm left travelling on my own
cos there's no-one else.
There's me.
You've seen how dangerous it is.
D'you wanna go home?
I don't know.
I want...
Can you smell chips?
Yeah.
Yeah! I want chips.
Me too. Right, then. Before
you get me back in that box, chips
it is. And you can pay. No money.
What sort of date are you? Come on,
then, tightwad. Chips are on me.
We've only got five billion years
till the shops close.
Now - you've seen the future,
so let's have a look at the past.
1860, how does 1860 sound?
What happened in 1860?
I don't know. Let's find out.
..I can't believe she's gone.
Not gone, Mr Redpath, sir.
Merely sleeping.
She's up and on her feet and out
there somewhere. Mr Sneed for shame,
how many more times? It's ungodly!
'... Excuse me, sir.
Mr Dickens, this is your call.'
..Use the sight. Find the old lady
or you're dismissed.
What phantasmagoria is this?
That's more like it!
Subtitles by BBC Broadcast - 2005